Saviour Godwin Etefia

System Software Engineer

Email: saviouretefia7@gmail.com
Phone:
+2347017342363

Profile Summary

I am a system software engineer with close to two years of experience in managing and optimizing business infrastructure. Experience includes ensuring business reliability and performance through maintenance, troubleshooting, developing full-stack dashboards as well as automating reports, utilizing tools such as SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript and other technologies to streamline processes for business analysis in order to enhance business efficiency.

Professional Experience

Huawei Technology Co. Ltd.

Lagos, Nigeria

System Software Engineer, (October 2022 - Present)

- Performed regular business maintenance activities, including monitoring, troubleshooting and resolving faults with business tools which includes full-stack dashboards and automated reports used in business and data analysis.
- Utilized business tools to analyze business KPIs in other to implement full-stack dashboards serving as a means of monitoring various business KPIs.
- Implemented and deployed automation tools for manual tasks such as daily reports using HTML, CSS and JavaScript resulting in improved business operational efficiency.
- Performed root cause analysis of report issues such as automated email failure, email configuration or re-modification as well as dashboard related issue by providing solutions.
- Assisted the development team to debug and report issues pertaining to migrations.

Huawei Technology Co. Ltd.

Lagos, Nigeria

NYSC - National Youth Service Corps (November 2021 - September 2022)

- Contributed to enhancing network security by incorporating cybersecurity redlines guidelines in network maintenance processes.
- Developed and implemented full-stack dashboards and automated services using JavaScript and other relevant technologies, worked with providers for managing state across the app
- Learned how to use and consume REST APIs to fetch data from backend to the client side.
- Developed and maintained SQL scripts and queries for data extraction, transformation and loading processes.

Skills

Technical Skills:

- Programming tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery
- Tools: Visual Studio Code, Git
- Microsoft Office Suite: Microsoft word, Excel, and Power point
- Database: SQL
- Quality Assurance (QA) documentation

Soft Skills:

- Strong verbal and written communication skills.
- Problem Solving
- Multitasking

Education and Certification

McPherson University, Ogun state, Nigeria. BSc Computer Science Completed (2017 - 2021)

Cyber Security for Service Work (Huawei) (October 2022)

Remote Delivery Certification (Huawei) (October 2022)

Preposition Competence Certification for Maintenance Service (Huawei) (October 2022)